[
  {
    "ReactMcq": [
      {
        "question": "Select Javascript library?",
        "answers": [
          "Angular",
          "React",
          "Redux",
          "Vue"
        ],
        "correct": "React",
        "questionId": "101"
      },
      {
        "question": "Styling is used to?",
        "answers": [
          "Add logic",
          "Attractive",
          "look simple",
          "none of above"
        ],
        "correct": "Attractive",
        "questionId": "102"
      },
      {
        "question": "ReactJS is an MVC based framework?",
        "answers": [
          "True",
          "False"
        ],
        "correct": "True",
        "questionId": "103"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is ReactJS?",
        "answers": [
          "Server-side Framework",
          "User-interface framework",
          "Both",
          "None"
        ],
        "correct": "Both",
        "questionId": "104"
      },
      {
        "question": "How can you access the state of a component from inside of a member function?",
        "answers": [
          " this.getState()",
          " this.prototype.stateValue",
          "this.state",
          "this.values"
        ],
        "correct": "this.values",
        "questionId": "105"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is a react.js in MVC?",
        "answers": [
          "Controller",
          "Middleware",
          "Model",
          "Router"
        ],
        "correct": "Controller",
        "questionId": "106"
      },
      {
        "question": "What does the “webpack” command do?",
        "answers": [
          "Transpiles all the Javascript down into one file",
          "Runs react local development server",
          "None",
          "Both A and B"
        ],
        "correct": "Transpiles all the Javascript down into one file",
        "questionId": "107"
      },
      {
        "question": "At the highest level, React components have lifecycle events that fall into",
        "answers": [
          "Initialization",
          "State/Property Updates",
          "Destruction",
          "All of these"
        ],
        "correct": "All of these",
        "questionId": "108"
      },
      {
        "question": "ReactJS covers _________",
        "answers": [
          "User Interface layer in an application",
          "Data layer in an application",
          "Both a and b",
          "None of above"
        ],
        "correct": "User Interface layer in an application",
        "questionId": "109"
      },
      {
        "question": "ReactJS uses _____ to increase performance",
        "answers": [
          "Virtual DOM",
          "Original DOM",
          "Both of above",
          "None of above"
        ],
        "correct": "Virtual DOM",
        "questionId": "110"
      },
      {
        "question": "Number of elements, a valid react component can return",
        "answers": [
          "1",
          "2",
          "3",
          "4"
        ],
        "correct": "1",
        "questionId": "111"
      },
      {
        "question": "State in react is________",
        "answers": [
          "A permanent storage",
          "Internal storage of the component",
          "Both of above",
          "None of above"
        ],
        "correct": "Internal storage of the component",
        "questionId": "112"
      },
      {
        "question": "props in react can________",
        "answers": [
          "Be changed inside the component",
          "Not be changed in the component",
          "Be changed in side other component",
          "None of above"
        ],
        "correct": "Not be changed in the component",
        "questionId": "113"
      },
      {
        "question": "In ReactJS, props can be used to pass",
        "answers": [
          "Properties to the component",
          "Event handler to component",
          "Both of above",
          "None of above"
        ],
        "correct": "Both of above",
        "questionId": "114"
      }
    ],
    "HtmlMcq": [
      {
        "question": "HTML stands for?",
        "answers": [
          "Hyper languange",
          "Hyperspeach languange",
          "Hypertext markup language",
          "none"
        ],
        "correct": "Hypertext markup language",
        "questionId": "101"
      },
      {
        "question": "The correct sequence of HTML tags for starting a webpage is -",
        "answers": [
          "Head, Title, HTML, body",
          "HTML, Body, Title, Head",
          "HTML, Body, Head, Title",
          "HTML, Head, Title, Body"
        ],
        "correct": "HTML, Head, Title, Body",
        "questionId": "102"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following tag is used to insert a line-break in HTML?",
        "answers": [
          "<br>",
          "<a>",
          "<pre>",
          "<b>"
        ],
        "correct": "<br>",
        "questionId": "103"
      },
      {
        "question": "How to create a hyperlink in HTML?",
        "answers": [
          "<a href=#> webshine.com </a>",
          "<a url=#> webshine.com </a>",
          "<a link=#> webshine.com </a>",
          "<a to=#> webshine.com </a>"
        ],
        "correct": "<a href=#> webshine.com </a>",
        "questionId": "104"
      },
      {
        "question": "How to insert an image tag in HTML?",
        "answers": [
          "img",
          "image",
          "<img />",
          "<src />"
        ],
        "correct": "<img />",
        "questionId": "105"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following tag is used to define options in a drop-down selection list?",
        "answers": [
          "<select>",
          "<list>",
          "<dropdown>",
          "<option>"
        ],
        "correct": "<option>",
        "questionId": "106"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following attribute is used to provide a unique name to an element?",
        "answers": [
          "<p>",
          "id",
          "type",
          "None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "id",
        "questionId": "107"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following HTML tag is the special formatting tag?",
        "answers": [
          "<p>",
          "<b>",
          "<pre>",
          "None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "<pre>",
        "questionId": "108"
      },
      {
        "question": "What are the types of unordered or bulleted list in HTML?",
        "answers": [
          "disc, square, triangle",
          "polygon, triangle, circle",
          "disc, circle, square",
          "All of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "disc, circle, square",
        "questionId": "109"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following HTML attribute is used to define inline styles?",
        "answers": [
          "style",
          "type",
          "class",
          "None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "style",
        "questionId": "110"
      },
      {
        "question": "In HTML5, which of the following tag is used to initialize the document type?",
        "answers": [
          "<Doctype HTML>",
          "<Doctype html />",
          "<Doctype>",
          "<!DOCTYPE html>"
        ],
        "correct": "<!DOCTYPE html>",
        "questionId": "111"
      },
      {
        "question": "The tags in HTML are -",
        "answers": [
          "case-sensitive",
          "in upper case",
          "not case sensitive",
          "in lowercase"
        ],
        "correct": "not case sensitive",
        "questionId": "112"
      },
      {
        "question": "A program in HTML can be rendered and read by -",
        "answers": [
          "Web browser",
          "Server",
          "Interpreter",
          "None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "Web browser",
        "questionId": "113"
      },
      {
        "question": "Fundamental HTML Block is known as ___________.",
        "answers": [
          "HTML Body",
          "HTML Tag",
          "HTML Attribute",
          "HTML Element"
        ],
        "correct": "HTML Body",
        "questionId": "114"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which HTML tag produces the biggest heading?",
        "answers": [
          "<h7>",
          "<h9>",
          "<h4>",
          "<h1>"
        ],
        "correct": "<h1>",
        "questionId": "115"
      },
      {
        "question": "Tags and texts that are not directly displayed on the page are written in _____ section.",
        "answers": [
          "<head>",
          "<title>",
          "<body>",
          "<html>"
        ],
        "correct": "<head>",
        "questionId": "116"
      },
      {
        "question": "HTML tags are surrounded by which type of brackets.",
        "answers": [
          "Curly",
          "Round",
          "Squart",
          "Angle"
        ],
        "correct": "Angle",
        "questionId": "117"
      },
      {
        "question": "In which part of the HTML metadata is contained?",
        "answers": [
          "body tag",
          "html tag",
          "head tag",
          "title tag"
        ],
        "correct": "head tag",
        "questionId": "118"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following is not supported in HTML5?",
        "answers": [
          "scheme",
          "content",
          "http-equiv",
          "name"
        ],
        "correct": "scheme",
        "questionId": "119"
      },
      {
        "question": "<input> is -",
        "answers": [
          "a format tag.",
          "an empty tag.",
          "All of the above",
          "None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "an empty tag.",
        "questionId": "120"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following tag is used to make the underlined text?",
        "answers": [
          "<i>",
          "<ul>",
          "<u>",
          "<pre>"
        ],
        "correct": "<u>",
        "questionId": "121"
      },
      {
        "question": "How to create a checkbox in HTML?",
        "answers": [
          "<input type = `checkbox`>",
          "<input type = `checked`>",
          "<checkbox>",
          "<input type = `check`>"
        ],
        "correct": "<input type = `checkbox`>",
        "questionId": "122"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following tag is used to define options in a drop-down selection list?",
        "answers": [
          "<select>",
          "<list>",
          "<dropdown>",
          "<option>"
        ],
        "correct": "<option>",
        "questionId": "123"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following tag is used to add rows in the table?",
        "answers": [
          "<td> and </td>",
          "<th> and </th>",
          "<tr> and </tr>",
          "None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "<tr> and </tr>",
        "questionId": "124"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following HTML tag is used to display the text with scrolling effect?",
        "answers": [
          "<marquee>",
          "<scroll>",
          "<div>",
          "None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "<marquee>",
        "questionId": "125"
      },
      {
        "question": "The <hr> tag in HTML is used for -",
        "answers": [
          "new line",
          "vertical ruler",
          "new paragraph",
          "horizontal ruler"
        ],
        "correct": "horizontal ruler",
        "questionId": "126"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following is the container for <tr>, <th>, and <td> ?",
        "answers": [
          "<data>",
          "<table>",
          "<group>",
          "All of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "<table>",
        "questionId": "127"
      },
      {
        "question": "What are the types of unordered or bulleted list in HTML?",
        "answers": [
          "disc, square, triangle",
          "polygon, triangle, circle",
          "disc, circle, square",
          "All of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "disc, circle, square",
        "questionId": "128"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following HTML attribute is used to define inline styles?",
        "answers": [
          "style",
          "type",
          "class",
          "None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "style",
        "questionId": "129"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following is the paragraph tag in HTML?",
        "answers": [
          "<p>",
          "<b>",
          "<pre>",
          "None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "<p>",
        "questionId": "130"
      },
      {
        "question": "An HTML program is saved by using the ____ extension.",
        "answers": [
          ".ht",
          ".html",
          ".hml",
          "None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": ".html",
        "questionId": "131"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following are the attributes of the tag?",
        "answers": [
          "method",
          "action",
          "Both (a) & (b)",
          "None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "Both (a) & (b)",
        "questionId": "132"
      },
      {
        "question": "A program in HTML can be rendered and read by -",
        "answers": [
          "Web browser",
          "Server",
          "Interpreter",
          "None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "Web browser",
        "questionId": "133"
      },
      {
        "question": "Any part of the graphic that is not included in another hot zone is considered to be part of",
        "answers": [
          "rect",
          "point",
          "default",
          "polygon"
        ],
        "correct": "default",
        "questionId": "134"
      },
      {
        "question": "The tag which allows you to rest other HTML tags within the description is",
        "answers": [
          "<TH>",
          "<TD>",
          "<TR>",
          "<CAPTION>"
        ],
        "correct": "<CAPTION>",
        "questionId": "135"
      },
      {
        "question": "Character encoding is",
        "answers": [
          "method used to represent numbers in a character",
          "method used to represent character in a number",
          "a system that consists of a code which pairs each character with a pattern,sequence of natural numbers or electrical pulse in order to transmit the data",
          "none of these"
        ],
        "correct": "a system that consists of a code which pairs each character with a pattern,sequence of natural numbers or electrical pulse in order to transmit the data",
        "questionId": "136"
      },
      {
        "question": "www is based on which model?",
        "answers": [
          "Local-server",
          "Client-server",
          "3-tier",
          "All of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "Client-server",
        "questionId": "137"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following attributes of text box control allow to limit the maximum character?",
        "answers": [
          "size",
          "len",
          "maxlength",
          "all of these"
        ],
        "correct": "maxlength",
        "questionId": "138"
      }
    ],
    "CssMcq": [
      {
        "question": "Pseudo-classes In CSS",
        "answers": [
          "Match A Specified Element",
          "Select The Active Links",
          "Are Used To Select All The Visited Links",
          "Are Used To Define A Special State Of An Element"
        ],
        "correct": "Are Used To Define A Special State Of An Element",
        "questionId": "101"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which Is The Correct CSS Syntax?",
        "answers": [
          "Body:color=black",
          "{body;color:black}",
          "{body:color=black(body}",
          "Body {color: Black}"
        ],
        "correct": "Body {color: Black}",
        "questionId": "102"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which CSS Property Is Used For Controlling The Layout?",
        "answers": [
          "Header",
          " Footer",
          "Display",
          "None Of The Above"
        ],
        "correct": "Display",
        "questionId": "103"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which CSS Property Sets A Background Image For An Element?",
        "answers": [
          "Background - Color",
          "Background - Image",
          "Background - Attachment",
          "None of These"
        ],
        "correct": "Background - Image",
        "questionId": "104"
      },
      {
        "question": " Which Of The Following Properties Will We Use To Display Border Around A Cell Without Any Content ?",
        "answers": [
          "Noncontent-cell",
          "Blank-cell",
          "Empty-cell",
          "Void-cell"
        ],
        "correct": "Empty-cell",
        "questionId": "105"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which CSS Property Is Used To Control The Text Size Of An Element ?",
        "answers": [
          "Font-style",
          "Font-size",
          "Text-size",
          "Text-style"
        ],
        "correct": "Font-size",
        "questionId": "106"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following defines a measurement relative to a font's x-height?",
        "answers": [
          "%",
          "cm",
          "em",
          "ex"
        ],
        "correct": "ex",
        "questionId": "107"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following property serves as shorthand for the marker properties?",
        "answers": [
          "list-style-type",
          "list-style-position",
          "list-style-image",
          "list-style"
        ],
        "correct": "list-style",
        "questionId": "108"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following property is used to add or subtract space between the words of a sentence?",
        "answers": [
          "color",
          "letter-spacing",
          "direction",
          "word-spacing"
        ],
        "correct": "word-spacing",
        "questionId": "109"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following property is used to set the width of an image?",
        "answers": [
          "border",
          "height",
          "width",
          "--moz-opacity"
        ],
        "correct": "width",                                             
        "questionId": "110"
      },
      {
        "question": "HTML element h1 is used in CSS for styling then it is also called a?",
        "answers": [
          "Attribute",
          "Value",
          "Selector",
          "Tag"
        ],
        "correct": "Selector",
        "questionId": "111"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following property specifies the top padding of an element?",
        "answers": [
          "padding-bottom",
          "padding-top",
          "padding-left",
          "padding-right"
        ],
        "correct": "padding-top",
        "questionId": "112"
      },
      {
        "question": "In CSS, styling elements can be done by ?",
        "answers": [
          "id",
          "class",
          "tag",
          "All of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "All of the above",
        "questionId": "113"
      },
      {
        "question": "In CSS, font-size is a property-name which _____________ the font of text.",
        "answers": [
          "increases",
          "decreases",
          "Both A and B",
          "None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "Both A and B",
        "questionId": "114"
      },
      {
        "question": "CSS is created and maintained through a group of people within the W3C called the?",
        "answers": [
          "CSS Class Tag",
          "CSS Class Group",
          "CSS Working Group",
          "CSS Working Id"
        ],
        "correct": "CSS Working Group",
        "questionId": "115"
      },
      {
        "question": " Which of the following selector selects the elements that are checked?",
        "answers": [
          "E ~ F",
          "::after",
          ":checked",
          "none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "correct": ":checked",
        "questionId": "116"
      },
      {
        "question": "__________ has introduced text, list, box, margin, border, color, and background properties.",
        "answers": [
          "css",
          "html",
          "ajax",
          "php"
        ],
        "correct": "css",
        "questionId": "117"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following CSS property sets the opacity level for an element?",
        "answers": [
          "opacity",
          "transparency",
          "transparent",
          "all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "correct": "opacity",
        "questionId": "118"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following is an appropriate value for overflow element?",
        "answers": [
          "hidden",
          "auto",
          "scroll",
          "all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "correct": "all of the mentioned",
        "questionId": "119"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following property specifies the stack order of an element?",
        "answers": [
          "order",
          "z-index",
          "p-index",
          "auto"
        ],
        "correct": "z-index",
        "questionId": "120"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following property allows long words to be able to be broken and wrap onto the next line?",
        "answers": [
          "line-wrap",
          "break-word",
          "word-wrap",
          "word-break"
        ],
        "correct": "word-wrap",
        "questionId": "121"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following CSS property can be used to provide the flex-direction and flex-wrap properties?",
        "answers": [
          "flex",
          "flex-flow",
          "flex-wrap",
          "all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "correct": "flex-flow",
        "questionId": "122"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following property aligns the flexible container’s items when the items do not use all available space on the main-axis?",
        "answers": [
          "wrap-content",
          "fix-content",
          "adjust-content",
          "justify-content"
        ],
        "correct": "justify-content",
        "questionId": "123"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which property is used to add space inside the text field?",
        "answers": [
          "padding",
          "margin",
          "number",
          "password"
        ],
        "correct": "padding",
        "questionId": "124"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which one can animate the width of search input when get focus?",
        "answers": [
          "focus",
          "transition",
          "outline",
          "color"
        ],
        "correct": "transition",
        "questionId": "125"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which is not the property of CSS box model?",
        "answers": [
          "width",
          "height",
          "margin",
          "color"
        ],
        "correct": "color",
        "questionId": "126"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following is not the value for an unordered list?",
        "answers": [
          "disc",
          "square",
          "circle",
          "numeric"
        ],
        "correct": "numeric",
        "questionId": "127"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which is not a box-level element?",
        "answers": [
          "<p>",
          "<ul>",
          "<li>",
          "<b>"
        ],
        "correct": "<b>",
        "questionId": "128"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which should be used to overlay text on image with high contrast?",
        "answers": [
          "screen",
          "high contrast",
          "low contrast",
          "opaque"
        ],
        "correct": "screen",
        "questionId": "129"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following will move the image up and down?",
        "answers": [
          "repeat-x",
          "fixed",
          "scroll",
          "repeat-y"
        ],
        "correct": "scroll",
        "questionId": "130"
      },
      {
        "question": "ID selector name is preceded by __________",
        "answers": [
          "‘.’",
          "‘%’",
          "‘#’",
          "‘@’"
        ],
        "correct": "‘#’",
        "questionId": "131"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following css property specifies a delay for the transition effect?",
        "answers": [
          "transition-delay",
          "transition-effect",
          "transition",
          "transition-duration"
        ],
        "correct": "transition-delay",
        "questionId": "132"
      }
    ],
    "JsMcq": [
      {
        "question": "Which type of JavaScript language is ___",
        "answers": [
          "Object-Oriented",
          "Object-Based",
          "Assembly-language",
          "High-level"
        ],
        "correct": "Object-Based",
        "questionId": "101"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which one of the following also known as Conditional Expression:",
        "answers": [
          "Alternative to if-else",
          "Switch statement",
          "If-then-else statement",
          "immediate if"
        ],
        "correct": "immediate if",
        "questionId": "102"
      },
      {
        "question": "In JavaScript, what is a block of statement?",
        "answers": [
          "Conditional block",
          "block that combines a number of statements into a single compound statement",
          "both conditional block and a single statement",
          "block that contains a single statement"
        ],
        "correct": "block that combines a number of statements into a single compound statement",
        "questionId": "103"
      },
      {
        "question": "When interpreter encounters an empty statements, what it will do:",
        "answers": [
          "Shows a warning",
          "Prompts to complete the statement",
          "Throws an error",
          "Ignores the statements"
        ],
        "correct": "Ignores the statements",
        "questionId": "104"
      },
      {
        "question": "The function and var are known as:",
        "answers": [
          "Keywords",
          "Data types",
          "Declaration statements",
          "Prototypes"
        ],
        "correct": "Declaration statements",
        "questionId": "105"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following variables takes precedence over the others if the names are the same?",
        "answers": [
          "Global variable",
          "The local element",
          "The two of the above",
          "None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "The local element",
        "questionId": "106"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which one of the following is the correct way for calling the JavaScript code?",
        "answers": [
          "Preprocessor",
          "Triggering Event",
          "RMI",
          "Function/Method"
        ],
        "correct": "Function/Method",
        "questionId": "107"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following type of a variable is volatile?",
        "answers": [
          "Mutable variable",
          "Dynamic variable",
          "Volatile variable",
          "Immutable variable"
        ],
        "correct": "Mutable variable",
        "questionId": "108"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following option is used as hexadecimal literal beginning?",
        "answers": [
          "00",
          "0x",
          "0X",
          "Both 0x and 0X"
        ],
        "correct": "Both 0x and 0X",
        "questionId": "109"
      },
      {
        "question": "In the JavaScript, which one of the following is not considered as an error:",
        "answers": [
          "Syntax error",
          "Missing of semicolons",
          "Division by zero",
          "Missing of Bracket"
        ],
        "correct": "Division by zero",
        "questionId": "101"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is a block statement in JavaScript?",
        "answers": [
          "conditional block",
          "block that contains a single statement",
          "both conditional block and a single statement",
          "block that combines multiple statements into a single compound statement"
        ],
        "correct": "block that contains a single statement",
        "questionId": "110"
      },
      {
        "question": "When an empty statement is encountered, a JavaScript interpreter __________",
        "answers": [
          "Ignores the statement",
          "Prompts to complete the statement",
          "Throws an error",
          "Shows a warning"
        ],
        "correct": "Ignores the statement",
        "questionId": "111"
      },
      {
        "question": "The “var” and “function” are __________",
        "answers": [
          "Keywords",
          "Declaration statements",
          "Data types",
          "Prototypes"
        ],
        "correct": "Declaration statements",
        "questionId": "112"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following option is used as hexadecimal literal beginning?",
        "answers": [
          "00",
          "0x",
          "0X",
          "Both 0x and 0X"
        ],
        "correct": "Both 0x and 0X",
        "questionId": "113"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following option is used as hexadecimal literal beginning?",
        "answers": [
          "00",
          "0x",
          "0X",
          "Both 0x and 0X"
        ],
        "correct": "Both 0x and 0X",
        "questionId": "114"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following option is used as hexadecimal literal beginning?",
        "answers": [
          "00",
          "0x",
          "0X",
          "Both 0x and 0X"
        ],
        "correct": "Both 0x and 0X",
        "questionId": "115"
      }

    ]
  }
]